准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
海绵宝宝呈现
潮间带
海星一家缩小记
你正在穿越一个海底次元
You are traveling through an aquatic dimension.
翻译 1440kHz
本字幕仅限学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
这个次元不仅有着欢笑
A dimension not only of laughs and giggles
还有止不住从鼻子笑喷出来的牛奶
but of uncontrollable nose milk.
等到一切开始疯狂
When things start to get coocoo
你就很有可能进入了
there's a pretty good chance you may have just entered
潮间带
"The Tidal Zone!"
我们回来了
And we're back!
《派大星秀》下一组嘉宾
Our next guest on "The Patrick Show"
派大星秀
是多才多艺的类
are the wonderfully talented Captain Quaaa...
类
Quaaa...
类星体船长与派大机
Captain Quasar and Pat-Tron!
欢迎参加本节目
Welcome to the show, fellas.
飞船不错
Cool spaceship.
你们是打哪来的
Where are you guys from?
外太空
Outer space.
脸太孔
Out her face?
不对  就是外太空
No. Just outer space.
外总比内强
Well, better out than in!
派大机  都跟你说了要关掉罐头笑声
Pat-Tron, I told you to turn off your laugh track.
罐头笑声会害他齿轮受损
It always strips his gears.
大家不用怕
Don't worry, folks.
我来修
I can fix it.
修不好
I can't fix it!
放我出去
Let me out!
排空机器肠道
Evacuating robo-bowels.
我脑瓜里卡了东西
I got something stuck to my melon.
是我的缩小射线
That's my shrink ray.
我还以为丢了
I thought I lost that.
射线害我头好辣
It's making my head all spicy!
站住  把缩小射线还给我
Stop! Give me back my shrink ray!
你们好  我的爱讲话主持人
Hola, my little chatty show hosts.
谁想点披萨
Who wants to order a pizza?
我要来份加菠萝和百花香的大号披萨
I'll take a large with pineapple and potpourri.
[ 百花香：由干燥的天然芳香植物材料混合制成
有一种特殊的味道 ]
还给你
Here you go.
现场观众不用怕
Fear not, studio audience.
我会帮他们解除缩小
I will unshrink them
用我飞船里的生长射线
with the growth ray I have in my ship.
我们房子变得好巨大
Our house is gigantic now!
这是我口香糖
Here's my gum!
好有电影感
And so cinematic.
十分电大感
It's cine-gigantic!
这还算话吗
Is that even a word?
邦妮别逗大水儿了  当然不算话
Don't be retupulous, Bunny, of course not.
变小一定会很有趣大感
Being small is gonna be fun-gigantic!
最后一个到大臭袜那边的
Last one to the big, stinky sock
变烂鱼卵
is a rotten fish egg!
好好笑  老爸
Good one, Dad!
要跳吗
Shall we?
小小小小小小小
Small, small, small, small, small, small, small
微小
Diminutive.
细小
Tiny.
渺小
Puny.
小不隆冬
Itty-bitty.
小不点儿
Teensy-weensy.
小
Small.
可爱
Lovely.
别闹了  阿尿
Not now, Tinkle!
希望派大爷也能来一起玩
I wish GrandPat were here to enjoy this.
你好
Hello!
学校慢行
就不能让老人家
Can't an old man
安安静静玩暴力游戏吗
play violent video games in peace anymore?
水
Water?
我们缩小了
We got shrunk.
派大爷
Hey, GrandPat!
可以帮忙取下小号毛巾吗
Can you get us some tiny towels?
害虫
Vermin?
这就用除虫口气逮住你们
I'll get you with my bug spray breath!
派大爷  不要
GrandPat! No!
跑哪去了
Where'd they go?
你们可以安全在这避难  海星一家
You'll be safe in here, Stars.
刚才真是好险
That was a close shave.
谢谢你们救了咱的小命
Thank you for saving us.
没错
Yeah.
我们替派大爷道歉
We apologize for GrandPat.
他以为我们是害虫
He thinks we're vermin.
对  跟你们一样
Yeah. Like you.
不用担心
No worries.
我们只是围坐在一起
We were just sitting down
准备吃烤薄荷糖
to eat our roasted peppermint.
量不算多  不过我们愿意跟你们分享
It's not much, but we're willing to share it with you.
分享什么
Share what?
派大星  注意礼貌
Patrick! Manners!
薄荷味
Minty.
我去开
I'll get it!
希望还有客人要来
I do hope it's more guests.
厨房
看到你们了
I see you!
派大爷
GrandPat?
要想在野外生存
To survive in the wild
最好远离家庭矛盾
we find it best to stay out of family squabbles.
飞镖鱼一家  分散逃跑
Dartfishes, scatter!
接招
Take that!
派大爷把新朋友吓跑了
GrandPat scared our new friends away.
他这次太过分了
This time he's gone too far.
那他亲爱的家人们
Then I guess his beloved family
一定要来好好教训他了
is gonna have to teach him a lesson.
就是我们  对吧
That's us, right?
什么
What?
捉害虫可气死又饿死我了
All this pest-huntin' is making me hangry.
来找找
Let's see here.
蛋糕模具来了
Cake molds away!
你们可恶
Why you--
可恶的小
Why those little--
害虫要复仇是吗
Revenge of the vermin, eh?
你
You!
害虫比我家人还聪明
These insects are smarter than my family.
行了  不当好老头了
That's it! No more Mr. Nice Geezer!
假牙  去咬它们
Dentures, go get 'em!
嗨
Hi.
我是鲁布多
I am Rube-dor.
我用高科技缩小吸收器
I shrunk you down with my futuristic shrink suckers
救了你们
to save you from harm.
谢谢  鲁布多
Thanks, Rube-dor.
为你们介绍闪光之城舒曼多
And to introduce you
to the shimmering, shiny city of Shmandor.
舒曼多是个好地方
Shmandor is the place to be.
舒曼多食物美味
Shmandor has fine dining
住房宽敞
spacious homes
交通系统一流
a state-of-the-art transit system
照相机 袜子 凉鞋
购物中心好物满满
shopping centers.
舒曼多位于深海  十分方便
And conveniently located under the sea
整座城市完全由手工吹制玻璃打造
Shmandor is entirely made of hand-blown glass.
太神了
Amazing.
天啊  可以在这定居吗
Oh, boy, can we live here?
当然可以了  孩子们
Sure, we can, kids.
舒曼多好美  让我好想
Shmandor is so beautiful, it makes me feel like...
唱歌
Singing
慢着
Hold on!
舒曼多不可以唱歌
There's no singing allowed in Shmandor!
这就是原因
And that's why!
恶心
Yuck.
不能唱歌的地方怎么住得了
Who wants to live in a place where you can't sing?
真是好险啊
That was a close one
更险的来了
And here comes a closer one
我们太小  碾不到
We're too small to be run over.
如果我是脏跳蚤  会躲在哪呢
Now, where would I hide if I was a filthy flea?
该来继续狠狠教训派大爷了
I think it's time to resume GrandPat's lesson.
我在派大机里面学来的
I picked this one up inside Pat-tron.
滑板车闹鬼了
My scooter is haunted!
别整我轮子  不然就烤了你们这群鬼
Quit spookin' my wheels or I'll roast you ghosts!
埃及  我爱埃及
Egypt? I love Egypt!
可我恨木乃伊
But I hate mummies!
一定要回家
I gotta get home!
真好玩
That was fun
可我们这么小  观众看不到怎么办
but what if we're too small for the audience to see us?
大家来看看我找到什么了
Hey, guys, look what I found.
海草与珊瑚巨大生长肥料
巨大生长肥料
Jumbo Grow plant food!
派大星  小心
Patrick, be careful!
要长大了
It's time to grow up!
现在小字看得到了  派大星
Now I can see the fine print, Patrick.
警告 本品可使生长缓慢植物长大
若使用于其他物品将会缩小
肥料会让植物长大  但会让人缩小
It grows plants, but it shrinks people.
你把大家缩成亚原子级别的大小了
You shrunk us down
to the sub-atomic teensy-weensy level.
今晚的节目演不完了
Now I'll never finish tonight's show.
团结起来  海星一家
Stay together, Stars.
这里应该有出口
I think there's a way out of here!
看  回家了
Look, we're home.
一切都恢复正常了
Everything's back to normal.
对吧
Right?
对
Right!
只不过月球变大眼球了
Except the Moon is a big eyeball now.
微生物太迷人了
Micro-critters are fascinatin'.
大泡弹
它们是怎么做到这么精密复杂
How can be they be so sophisticated
还能这么小的
when they're so dang little?
很高兴没人在看着我
Glad no one's watchin' me.
旁白奶奶常常教导我
Grandma Frenchy always said
别为小事斤斤计较
"Don't sweat the small stuff."
在这个小小的世界里
And in this small world
浓缩的小东西都是精华
where good things come in small packages
不难理解  小小的细节决定成败
it's no small wonder
that it's the little things that mean a lot.
尽在这小小的凌晨时光里的
Especially in the wee small hours of
潮间带
"The Tidal Zone."
欢迎来到
二进制村
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
请你想象
Imagine if you will
小镇裤头村
the town of Bikini Bottom
现在来想象这里的居民都是机器人
Now imagine if everyone who lived there was a robot
为你呈现
Submitted for your approval
裤头村
二进制村之旅
a trip to Binary Bottom
二进制村
我准准  准备好了
I'm re-re-ready
我准准  备好了
I'm red-red-ready
油
早安  海绵机
Morning, SpongeBot
你今天样子真帅气
You're looking handsome today
早
Good--
早安  机器蜗
good morning, Robo-Gary
你想玩啊
You wanna play
我知道你想玩什么
I know what you want
小蜗  对激光温柔一点
Gary, be gentle with the little laser
工作
该去上班了  小蜗
Time for work, Gary
等我回家了我再来跟你玩
I'll play with you more when I get home
不行  小蜗
No, no, Gare-bearings
必须待在家里
You have to stay here at home
往左边一点点
A little more to the left
快好了
Almost there
完完完美
P-p-p-perfect
再见  小小小蜗
See you later, G-G-G-Gary
终于
Finally
有个能让我快快乐乐陪在身边的人
someone whose company I actually enjoy--
我
me
该上班了  章鱼机
Time for work, Squidbot
给我断电滚远点  海绵机
Power down and leave me alone, SpongeBot
我只剩十五分钟了
I've still got 15 minutes
抱歉  章鱼机
Sorry, Squidbot
走开
Go away
我得住那家伙隔壁
I am going to have to live next to that?
自爆
敲敲门
Knock, knock, knock
派大机  我要去上班了
Hey Pat-Tron, I'm going to work
我跟你一起走  海绵机
I'm going with you, SpongeBot
我得补充燃料
I gotta fuel up
万岁
Hooray
派大机正处于充电模式
Pat-Tron is currently in recharge mode
好了  兄弟
OK, buddy
我回家会给你带燃料回来的
I'll bring you some fuel on my way back home
要是非得迟到的话  就把钥匙给我
If you're going to be late, give me the key
抱歉  章鱼机
Sorry, Squidbot
不过
But
我钥匙骨头连着手指骨头  给不了
The key bone's connected to the finger bone
电池王
你被开除了
You're fired
谢了  小子
Thank you, Bot-O
我刚卡在开除模式了
I got stuck in the firing mode
要被开除了
To be fired
没人会被开除  你个机器懒鬼
Nobody's getting fired, you robo-loafer
所有人去工作
Everybody get to work
电池堡煎得滋滋作响
The Krabby Batteries are sizzlin'
来加调料了
Now it's time for condiments
快上菜  海绵机
Food up, SpongeBot
快来两份电池堡  加洋葱
Gimme two batteries on a barge and make 'em cry
机器蜗
Robo-Gary?
章鱼机
Squidbot?
不
No
蜗鱼章
Gary-Squid?
章鱼蜗
Squid-Gary?
无法计算
Does not compute
把你家脏兮兮的机器蜗牛弄下去
Get your filthy robo-snail off my head
小蜗
Gary
油之霸
迟早要给这条随地大便的寄生虫断电
I've gotta cut off this pooping parasite
好了  这到底是怎么回事
All right, what the kelp is going on in here?
给我回来  你们这群镀镍的傻蛋
Come back here, you nickel-plated nincompoops
痞老机  你又忘了上发条了
Plankbot, you forgot to wind yourself again
谢谢你  凯伦
Thanks, Karen
我的血肉之躯老婆
my flesh and blood wife
你放心  我会抓到他的
Don't worry, I'll get him
嗨  凯伦
Hi, Karen
小蜗有经过这里吗
Did Gary come through here?
他往那边走了  爱笑鬼
He went thataway, Chuckles
谢谢谢  谢谢你
Th-th-th-thank you
我妈交代过我千万别嫁机器人
Mama told me not to marry a robot
快让开
Gangway
机器人出逃
Runaway robot
不好意思  借过一下
Excuse me, pardon me
是谁侵扰了珊卓的神圣电子屋
Who disturbs the sacred dome of Sandroid?
我要捆住你们的传动装置
I'll hogtie your actuators
珊卓  等等
Sandroid, wait
小蜗还年轻  传动装置千万不能捆
Gary is too young to have his actuators hogtied
我要黑进你们的硬件
I'll hack your hard drives
你们这群自动化白痴
you cybernetic simpletons
好了  可以了
All right, there you go
欢迎来到润乐湖
热狗
机器狗
Robo-dog
来买机器狗
Get your robo-dog
润乐湖
Lube Lagoon?
酷乐湖怎么了
What happened to Goo Lagoon?
我在哪个时空来着
Where in space and time am I?
看来我在前一次大灾变那边转错弯了
Looks like I took a wrong turn at the last apocalypse.
危险
Danger
机器暴民
Rogue Robot
小蜗  等等
Gary, wait
回来
Come back
谁这么大胆  敢侵犯珊卓
Who dares defy Sandroid?
我要毁灭你们所有人
I'm gonna destroy all of you
这群破铜烂铁想要我赘肉当燃料
These junk heaps want my flab for fuel!
不要  小蜗
No, Gary
别进润乐湖
Not the lagoon
该怎么办
What do I do now?
想想办法
Got to think
想
有了
That's it
搭砖墙
A brick wall
火箭
小蜗
Gary
停
Stop
小蜗  停
Gary, stop
停
小蜗  停
Gary, stop
小蜗不会停的
He's not gonna stop
跟机器蝶好好玩
Play nice with the flutterbot
太神了
Amazing
禁止在珊卓面前开闪光灯拍照
Flash photography is forbidden
in the presence of Sandroid
你们全部都要让我同化
You will all be assimilated
这样就可以亲亲密密在一起了
So we can all be as close as peas in a pod
太神
Ama--
你害我又被大铁怪困住了
Well, this is another
fine metallic monstrosity you've got me into
往好的方面看  章鱼机
Look at it this way, Squidbot
现在就有机会跟所有邻居叙叙旧了
Now we'll have a chance
to catch up with all our neighbors
嗨  鲁布
Hi, Rube
你好啊
Well, hello
果不其然
Typical
机器人崛起
Rise of the robots
我附议
I second that
你说机器人无法取代我们
Robots can never replace us, you say?
然而动画片里一切皆有可能
Well, anything can happen in a cartoon
而这部动画片则来自
especially if that cartoon is from
潮间带
"The Tidal Zone"
交换有故障
翻译 1440kHz
闪电莓  闪电莓
Lightning berries, lightning berries
我在扫描闪电莓
I'm scanning for lightning berries
本字幕仅限学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
摘给亲爱痞老板
For dear, old, Mr. Plankton
找到了
Bingo!
露营家派大星
Camper Patrick!
你居然把闪电莓都吃了
I can't believe you ate all the lightning berries.
谁在说话
Who said that?
那是我帽子吗
Is that my hat?
不  先等一下
No. Wait, just a sec--
闪电莓
Lightning berries
与凯伦的计算机电路
and Karen's computer circuitry.
这奇妙的组合
A potent combination
将导致一场震惊无比的意识交换
which results in a shocking mind switch.
这种常事  尽在
A common occurrence here in...
潮间带
"The Tidal Zone."
然后珊迪说“好”
And then Sandy said "yeah"
哈维说“好”
and Harvey goes "yeah."
然后凯文说“好”
And then Kevin said "yeah."
大家都在说好
Everybody was saying yeah.
够了
Enough!
你干嘛找我说话
Why are you talking to me?
我在留下美好回忆呢
I'm making memories.
给我记好了
Well, remember this.
凯伦
Karen!
总算来了
There she is!
你都去哪了
Where the heck have you been?
我要的闪电莓在哪
And where are those lightning berries I asked you for?
我吃了
I ate them.
你在说什么胡话
What are you talking about?
你吃不了东西
You know you don't eat.
快带我回家去
Now take me home.
兄弟
Hey, buddy.
快点  要迟到了
Come on. We're late.
天啊
Golly.
滑得不错
Sweet ride.
你还挺会过日子
You really know how to live.
你们好啊
Howdy, boys.
来得正好
You're just in time.
我就快把游戏摆好了
I'm almost done setting up the game.
怎么回事
What the heck?
我的意识
My mind
一定跟派大星的意识发生了交换
must've switched with Patrick's mind
都是闪电莓导致的结果
from the lightning berries.
有血有肉有大肚
Flesh and blood and guts.
我变模拟量了
I've gone analog.
原来这俩条是腿
So these are legs?
控制活生生的身体不算太难
A living body isn't so hard to control.
掌握诀窍了
I think I got this.
全都准备好开局了
All ready to play.
这可是我发明过最难的桌游了
This here's the toughest board game I ever invented.
要想获胜  就要了解数学
In order to win, you need to know math
科学  文学  还有历史
science, literature, and history.
2553025的平方根等于多少
What's the square root of 25,553,025?
5,055.
什么
What?
液体流速增大
The increase in speed of a liquid...
伯努利原理
The law of fluid dynamics.
后结构主义
Post-structuralism.
公元395年
395 AD.
亚特兰蒂斯的沉没
The sinking of Atlantis.
获胜
智多星
我赢了
I win!
好棒  凯伦
That's great, Karen.
实在太棒了
Real great.
现在我就只能拿辐射苹果
Now, I'll have to substitute radioactive apples...
代替闪电莓了
For the lightning berries.
那是我吗
Is that me?
我现在变轮滑鞋了吗
I'm a rollie shoe now?
好酷
Cool!
斜坡
Ramp.
我的海神王啊
Oh, my Neptune!
小心点
Watch it!
别闹了  帮我把这个切开
Stop fooling around and help me cut this open.
手术刀给我
Hand me a scalpel.
让我
Let me...
拿到了
I got it!
现在快拿给我
Now, hand it to me.
小心点
Careful!
里面都是硫
That's full of sulfuric...
酸
acid.
好了  赶紧给你重启吧
All right, time for a robot reboot.
给我回来
Get back here!
你中了什么邪  派大星
What's gotten into you, Patrick?
你今天不太像你自己
You don't seem like yourself today.
我不是我自己
Well, I'm not myself.
我是凯伦  痞老板的电脑助理
I'm Karen, Plankton's computer assistant
现在在派大星身体里
in Patrick's body.
我们的意识发生了交换
Our minds got switched
那时我们俩都被闪电莓电到了
when we were both electrified by lightning berries.
好家伙  意识交换
Hot diggity dog! A mind switch!
来分析一下  交换感觉如何
Let's analyze. What's it like?
待在派大星的身体里
Well, being in Patrick's body
让我体验到前所未有的感觉  像味觉
has opened up senses that I never had like taste.
来  尝个甜甜圈
Here, try a doughnut.
味觉加载中
加载完毕
好好吃
That's delicious!
这个有什么味道
What's this taste like?
这个也很好吃
That tastes pretty good too.
外面还有可以吃的东西吗
Are there more things to ingest out here?
我这是怎么了
What's happening to me?
这叫疼痛
That's called pain.
疼痛  好迷人
Pain. Fascinating.
快来
Come on.
踢踢我  让我多疼点
Kick me for more pain.
快回来
Get back here!
快给轮滑鞋让条道
Make way for the rollie shoe!
没什么好看的  继续做小屁孩去
Nothing to see here! Go back to your childhoods!
你在里面没事吧  凯伦
You okay in there, Karen?
嗅觉  不是很行
Sense of smell, not so great.
确实有趣过一阵子
Well, it's been interesting
不过总而言之
but all in all
还是变回电脑开心点
I'll be happy to be back in my old computer self.
我草草搭了这个设备
I rigged up this device
应该可以把你和派大星的意识换回去
that I think will switch you and Patrick's minds back.
我称之为纵横交错装置
I call it the crisscross contraption.
那是我身体
That's my body!
一定得把意识换回去
We have to swap our minds back!
你在说什么啊  我是轮滑鞋
What are you talking about? I'm a rollie shoe.
一辈子当轮滑鞋
Rollie shoe forever!
你休想
Not a chance.
我才是轮滑鞋
I'm rollie shoe!
在那边
Over there!
你们抓不到轮滑鞋
You can't catch the rollie shoe!
好了  派大星
Okay, Patrick.
我本来留着  当作有味觉的最后一餐
I was saving this for my last meal with tastebuds
但你赢了
but you win.
请你吃吧
So here you go.
冰淇淋
Ice cream!
我吃不到
I can't taste it!
我没嘴巴  可我必须吃冰淇淋
I have no mouth and I must ice cream!
好可怕的噩梦
This is a nightmare!
尝试哭泣
我再也不当轮滑鞋了
I don't want to be a rollie shoe anymore!
来碰碰运气
Here goes nothing.
凯伦  是你吗
Karen, is that you?
胡说
Duh!
没有用
It didn't work!
你还是那个粉红钉子头
You're still that pink pinhead.
骗到你了
Gotcha!
我为什么给你加了幽默感
Why did I give you a sense of humor?
快来
Come on.
一起回家吧
Let's go home.
现在已经皆大欢喜了  对吧派大星
All's well that ends well. Right, Patrick?
冰淇淋  给我给我给我
Ice cream! Gimme, gimme, gimme!
好奇怪
That's peculiar.
我变回来了
I'm me again.
各位
Guys?
新派大星们  等等我
Hey, new Patricks! Wait for me!
啊  夏令营
Ah, summer camp
每一位孩子都有自己独特的个性
where each child is unique in their own individual way.
而这一次例外
Except for this one time
尽在珊瑚营地  以及这个地方
in Kamp Koral and this one place.
什么地方  潮间带吗
What is this? "The Tidal Zone"?
免费电话有代价
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
各位艺术爱好者  大家好
Bonjour, art lovers
今晚  敬请欣赏
Tonight, for your viewing enjoyment
一幅以贪婪为基调的肖像画
we present a portrait painted in shades of greed
蟹堡王
新的一天  又赚得盆满钵满
Another day, another whole bunch of dollars
两毛五
A quarter
给我给我给我给我
Gimme, gimme, gimme, gimme
你给我回来
Come back here, you
你这是要去哪
Where are you going?
这两毛五害我累死了
This quarter is really making me work
给我回来
Get back here
你好  陌生人
Greetings, stranger.
欢迎光临我的奇迹商店
Welcome to my Emporium of Wonders.
我是否可以向你推荐一款传统的
Can I interest you in a traditional
可乐那族斯普拉丹可
Klopnodian Spladunker?
或者来一款九成新的弗洛纳
Or perhaps a lightly used Flooner?
不用了  老人家
No thanks, old timer
我只要我的两毛五
I just want me quarter
它好像跳进你公用电话去了
It seems to have hopped into your pay phone here
明白了
I see.
我没法帮你把硬币弄出来
Well I have no power to retrieve your coin
但我可以让公用电话归你
but I can let you have the payphone
价格低到
for the low, low price of...
免费
free.
Free?
我收下了
I'll take it
但请你注意  那公用电话有诅咒
But be warned, that payphone comes with a curse.
真的吗
Really?
诅咒一共多少钱
How much does the curse cost?
什么
What?
不用钱  诅咒是免费的
No, the curse is free.
随电话附赠的
It comes with the phone.
那就好
Well then
诅咒我也收下了
I'll take the curse, too
听我一句劝
Heed my Kapritzka!
小心门廊的来电
Beware the call of the porch!
小心
Beware!
算了吧
Forget it.
第二天早上
都听好了  快乐蟹堡客
Listen up, happy Krustomers
现在你们只要花两毛五
For the low price of a quarter, now you, too
也可以在蟹堡王打重要电话
can make that important call
同时吃蟹黄堡了
while you're eating a Krabby Patty
你好
Ahoy, there
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
我是店主尤金蟹
Eugene Krabs, proprietor, speaking
把蟹黄堡都送出去
Give away your Krabby Patties
全都送出去
Give them all away
这什么下流的骚扰电话
What kind of obscene phone call is this?
等我找到你是谁  我就
When I find out who you are, I'm gonna--
一定要送出蟹黄堡
Must give patties away
不要钱
No money
蟹黄堡免费
Patties free
免费蟹黄堡
Free patties?
蟹老板啊
Oh, Mr. Krabs
你总算找到你内心的慷慨大方了
You finally found your inner generosity
万岁
Hooray
蟹黄堡人人有份
Krabby Patties for everyone
蟹老板给大家请客
The Krab is picking up the tab
一律免费
All free
怎么回事
What just happened?
好啊
Oh, boy
两毛五
A quarter
就知道这玩意会有回报
I knew this thing would pay off
蟹黄堡来了
Patties here
免费蟹黄堡
Free patties
免费
快来趁热领取蟹黄堡
Get your patties while they're hot
快来趁免费领取蟹黄堡
Get 'em while they're free
免费
Free?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
蟹堡王没有免费午餐
There's no free lunches at the Krusty Krab
你这是疯了吗
Have you gone insane?
快回厨房去
Get back in the kitchen
把吃一半的蟹黄堡都缝起来
and stitch these patty halves back together
留着之后再卖出去
so we can sell 'em again
美好时光不长久
It was too good to last
蟹堡王  我是尤金
Krusty Krab, Eugene--
把钱都送出去
Now give away your money
一分不剩
Every last cent
一定要把钱送出去
Must give away money
把钱都送出去  小子
Give away all money, Boy-O
可你刚不是说
But you just said that--
就知道你只是在开玩笑  蟹老板
I knew you were only kidding, Mr. Krabs
你真的特别大方
You really are generous
又有两毛五
Another quarter
我好爱这电话
I love this phone
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
你拿我钱在干什么
What are you doing with me money?
你刚明明让我送钱的  蟹老板
Well, I thought you told me to, Mr. Krabs
我
I--
我不明白
I don't understand
现在  蟹老板
And now, Krabs
把蟹堡王送出去
give away the Krusty Krab
好啊
Yes
有了这个激光炮
With this laser cannon
终于可以炸掉老螃蟹了
I can finally blast Krabs
怎么回事
Homina-wha?
这是蟹堡王的地契
Here his deed to Krusty Krab
地契
全都归你了
She's all yours
好像有点不对劲
Something doesn't seem right here
不过痞奶奶常常教导我
But like Granny Plankton always says
不要拒绝别人的好意
never look a gift snail under the shell
我赢了
I win
我最棒
I'm the greatest
怎么
What the--
我两毛五呢
Where's me quarter?
也许慷慨大方本身就是回报
Perhaps generosity is its own reward?
不行
Never
你什么意思
What's the big idea?
你欠我那两毛五还给不
And where is that quarter you owe--
自由了
I'm free
小子  能借我两毛五坐公交车吗
Hey kid, lend me a quarter for the bus?
好啊  恶魔先生
Sure thing, Mr. Demon
终于自由了
I'm finally free
情况还不算太糟
Well, this ain't so bad
工作稳定  硬币管够
Steady work, and plenty of quarters
我这老螃蟹会习惯的
A crab could get used to this
怎么回事
What's going on?
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
能不能把那堆垃圾扔了
get that hunk of junk out of here, would you?
快点
Come on
可以
Gladly
喂  谁想打电话
Hello, anyone wanna make a call?
只要两毛五
Only costs a quarter
真见鬼
Barnacles
有时候  一部免费电话有极高的代价
Sometimes a free phone comes at a very high price
而有时候  小气鬼
and sometimes the cheapskates
则会吃到大亏
are the ones who get stuck with the bill
一切尽在  潮间带
here in "The Tidal Zone"
喂
Hello?
一定要再讲一个故事出来
Must give away one more story.
故事的主角是一位迷离时空的老爷爷
The story of a grandpa adrift in space and time.
同时又是一只海星  迷失在
The story of a sea star who is lost
潮间带
in "The Tidal Zone."
时空的皱纹
给我让开  致幻太空垃圾
Outta my way, you psychedelic space junk!
我的海神王啊
Sweet Neptune!
我这是找到宇宙起源了吗
Have I found the beginning of the universe?
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives a pineapple under the sea?
海星派大爷
Grandpat Sea Star!
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海星派大爷
Grandpat Sea Star!
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海星派大爷
Grandpat Sea Star!
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海星派大爷
Grandpat Sea Star!
准备
Ready?
海星派大爷
Grandpat Sea Star!
一定要逃离这场噩梦
I gotta get out of this nightmare!
蟹堡王 死鱼眼商店
这里一城不容我们二虎
This town ain't big enough for the both of us.
这个宝宝好漂亮
Now that's a good looking baby!
我到站了
Well, this is my stop.
再见了
See y'all later!
跑起来
Giddy-up, now!
一路顺风
Happy trails!
你好
Bonjour.
能回到这个正常的家  感觉真好
It's good to be back home where it's normal.
嗨  派大爷
Hi, Grandpat--
你在看什么
What you watching?
差不多
Close enough.
于是事情变得有一点点奇怪
And so we leave things a little bit weird
但却本该如此
but that's how we like it here
尽在潮间带
in "The Tidal Zone."
再见
Au revoir.
我还在看呢
I was watching that!